wta.org 2018-01-20

# Privacy Policy — Washington Trails Association

WTA's privacy policy, including collection of personal information and cookies. 

Washington Trails Association firmly respects your privacy and will attempt to handle that personal information about visitors is handled responsibly.

### Browsing our website

You can browse [www.wta.org](http://www.wta.org/), subject to our website [Terms of Service](http://www.wta.org/our-work/about/terms-of-service "Terms of Service"), without telling us who you are and without revealing any personal information. The only information we collect from an typical ordinary web site visit (one that does not involve a form submission) is your IP address, the pages you view and the date and time you view them. We use this information to measure site activity in order to improve the usefulness of our website to our visitors.

### Collection of personally identifiable information

Visitors must register in order to use certain features of our website, such as our Signpost Blog discussion forum. During registration, a visitor is required to provide contact information such as name, email address, and zip code. We use this information to verify the authenticity of your email, and we may on occasion contact visitors about features and services that we believe may be of interest.

When a visitor asks us to provide information or a service, we request information that enables us to respond to the visitor. This information could include contact information (such as name, mailing address, and email address) and, if applicable, financial, payment, or billing information.

Washington Trails Association may gather email addresses and other personally identifiable data about visitors when such data is voluntarily submitted to [www.wta.org](http://www.wta.org/). For example, our site uses submission forms for visitors to sign up for trail work or events; request information, services, or products; or to become a member. Email addresses from the submission form will be used only for the purpose of contacting you about the particular work party, event, online order or other interaction. You will receive unrelated emails only if you have specifically opted-in to one of our mailing lists at the time you provided it. Other contact information (e.g., mailing address) may be used to contact you about opportunities with the WTA that we feel may be of interest to you. Financial information is used to bill visitors in connection with their orders. WTA cannot insure against invasion by security breakers of any manner.

Washington Trails Association makes every effort to ensure the secure collection and transmission of sensitive user information using industry-accepted data collection and encryption methodologies.

Washington Trails Association does not sell, trade or otherwise disclose such user information outside our organization. However, if you become a member of Washington Trails Association, some information on our membership lists, such as your name and address, may be exchanged with other organizations. WTA members may opt out of such membership list exchanges.

### Cookies

A cookie is a small data file stored on a visitor's computer that contains information about the visitor. Like most websites, WTA may place a cookie in the browser files of a visitor's computer. We use persistent cookies to store your information when you sign up for a work party so that you will not have to re-enter it when you sign up again. We also use transient cookies to store items in your online store shopping cart and to enable access to our blog. If visitors decline to accept cookies, they may still use our site, but some portions of our site may be inaccessible.

### Use of Location Data

When you are using the Washington Trails Association's smartphone application or accessing this website on a mobile device, we may determine your current location and use that information to help you find nearby hikes. We do not share your location information with any third parties, nor do we use it for any purpose other than to determine your distance from the hikes in our database. If you are not comfortable with this, you may disable the use of location services in the application settings at any time. Please note that our smartphone application can also be used to obtain turn-by-turn directions to reach the hikes in our database. Using this functionality will not send your location information to the Washington Trails Association website, but it may result in your location data being sent to the provider of your phone's default mapping application.

### Use of Google Analytics

We have implemented Google Analytics features based on Display Advertising (ex: Remarketing, Google Adwords, Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting, etc.). We and other third-party vendors, including Google, use first-party cookies and third-party cookies together to report how your ad impressions, other uses of ad services, and interactions with these ad impressions and ad services are related to visits to our site.

Google Analytics does not store any visitor specific data, and we will not use visitor-specific data in any way related to Google Analytics, Google Adwords, and Remarketing. We use aggregated behavioral information to inform and refine our marketing efforts.

At any time, you may choose to opt-out of Google Analytics tracking with the [Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/%22%20%5Ct%20%22_blank). You can also opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads using the [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/%22%20%5Ct%20%22_blank).
